In our generation this awareness was something that we understood
pretty late but today's
generation is very smart
a such a big secret that after reading the book they said that
my 2 crores will come it does not happen I am
going to take care of all these things I don't have to worry much
welcome back to retire by the way you desire
in the previous episode we ask people about how their
planning will sustain them in this
final episode we are going to ask them how they
reached that number that is right what that big
number is so the big question for today how do they
arrive at the number they need to sustain themselves
and save for retirement c
that amount is never enough but I spoke to an
accountant friend of mine and he told me that
1.5 to 2 crores should be enough.
And but I feel that there should be a working
capital.  I mean a working thing which keeps
on growing.  I think today it is 1
crore but after five years it will be 5
crore you know you never know.
So a 10 year should be able to but I'm in
five years from now who knows what the
economy is going to be like or.
So basically I have thought that before my
retirement I should have at least Rs 1.5-2 crore savings.
That's nice.  Yeah.
And that should be enough to set up the farm
also.  You have taken the price of the form, right?
What will happen even after 15 years?
Yes, I mean right now with my working we will try to buy that
form and then we will
see what happens next.
The kind of lifestyle I'm looking at, I
think 200 million should be sufficient.  I'm not
really sure about it, but I think that's the
kind of figure that will be sufficient.   I
know how much travelling costs and have also saved a little
but the exact calculation as you say has
not been done yet.
So it's pretty simple to calculate.  Do you know
your monthly expenses?  Yes.  Factor the
inflation on top of that.
Keep some buffer.  That should give you a fairly
good idea as to how much money you would need
once you are retired month after month.  I
think simple as that.
Inflation is very important because I mean you got a that is
going to be minus from
all your earnings.
Absolutely.  And that's where most of the
people fail because they don't account for that.
But I guess we figured out something for sure.
Guest work doesn't work with retirement.  You
need personalized plans, all your
expenses, all your expectations, all of that
needs to be put into what I have been telling
you all the ICICI potential
life insurance, retirement calculator
and get the exact number that you need.
Thanks so much for joining us.  Make Sure
to Retire the Way You Desire.